Erdian Tomy Malewa

Digital Business Storyteller

tomymalewa@about.me

Publications

Escape Moment with The Winner

Green Sands September 13, 2013

Authors: Erdian Tomy Malewa

Tidak Berhasil Menjadi Comic, But I Love Stand Up Comedy

Metro TV

Authors: Erdian Tomy Malewa

Never #Shout never!

NYLON GUYS INDONESIA December 2013

Authors: Erdian Tomy Malewa

TiketTawa feature

Kompasiana, Kaskus etc.

Authors: Erdian Tomy Malewa

Summary

I have 8 years career in multinational banking, broadcasting media, digital marketing, community, and startup ecosystem. With that many experiences both successful and UNSUCCESSFUL story, i am a business person who love user experiences & gamification.

Specialties: Product & Business development 2.0

NOTE:

- The Paranoid person who spend too much time to think deeper, see further and do faster
- Professional extrovert, Personal introvert
- Product Creator, Brand Storyteller, Failed founders, Duathlon Amateur

Experience

Country Business Development at FreakOut Dewina Indonesia

October 2015 - Present (11 months)

Global digital marketing technology company from japan

- We are the first mobile native ads platform in Indonesia

We start new style ad network business (called "Native Ads Platform") focus on smartphone media in Indonesia.

- We connected Publisher & Advertiser and we deliver based on User Experiences.

Responsbilites:

- Serve as a key member of the executive team that sets the company's strategic direction.
- Spearhead business development initiatives that are consistent with the company's overall strategy.
- Manage multiple business initiatives in a start-up environment.
- Revenue generation and strategic partnerships development and management.
- Build and manage a business development team.

Angel Investor & Partner at DreamCodes Inc.

April 2016 - Present (5 months)

Helping for Business Strategy, Product Development & Innovation.

Software House Company that concern all about Gamification Industry. We translate your big data into personalized mobile games.

Co-founder at TOLONG.IN

May 2015 - May 2016 (1 year 1 month)

P2P Hyperlocal search engine "Tempat yang tepat untuk memberi & meminta TOLONG!"

The point why I build TOLONG.IN is that I want to be a 'smart volunteer' that can help with the right way, in a quick way, and also giving the advantage. Let's Help to each other!!

Senior Strategy Consultant at Mediatrac Sistem Komunikasi

August 2015 - September 2015 (2 months)

- Responsible for large scale, complex and long duration projects and project teams made up of internal and external resources to deliver business solutions and services.
- Work with assigned business group and technical teams to gather and evaluate project requirements, define project scopes and provide input to project map.
- Manage project resources and timeline, ensuring critical path milestones are met, identifying any barriers to progress and working with business representatives or other necessary party to mitigate problems.
- Lead project management from A to Z and evaluate performance of project team member (Junior & Associate Consultant)

- Sometimes referred to as new product development, the discipline is focused on developing systematic methods for guiding all the processes involved in getting a new product to market.
- I lead DIGITAL & CRM consultant team for the world's largest international tobacco company

Strategic Advisor at FreakOut, Inc.

August 2015 - September 2015 (2 months)

- Thinking Partner for Country Manager Indonesia.
- Advisor for Developing Team and Operation Strategy in Indonesia.
- Give an overview of mobile advertising landscape in indonesian market
- Monitoring

Key Account Manager at Touchten Games Pte. Ltd.

2015 - 2015 (less than a year)

- Focus on B2B Market
- Business Development for O2O (Online to Offline) Touchten Platform Games
- Identify and manage client leads.
- Build relationships with senior management within the client.
- Preparing and presenting materials for meetings presentations and status reports.
- Analyze existing accounts, identify customer-specific needs and develop a solution.
- Partnership with E-commerce, FMCG, Fashion Retail and etc
- Mission: make advertising more fun, friendly & targeted

Founder at TiketTawa.com

June 2013 - January 2014 (8 months)

TiketTawa.com is a website providing ticketing sale service special for an event or Stand Up Comedy performance in Indonesia. Officially collaborate with region area which has Stand Up Comedy community.

TiketTawa.com had been used in the 10 biggest city in Indonesia.

TiketTawa.com only served online sales using the newest system that made the consumen feel how easy to buy the online ticket fast and safely.

Tikettawa.com was closed (until uncertainty) because there was management changing, lost one of cofounder as a Head Programmer.

Ps: if you want to find a review or news about tikettawa by our former users, please googling with keywords " tikettawa.com " turn on filter just for blog/news feature.

Head of Marketing at Stereo Desserts

2014 - 2014 (less than a year)

http://www.stereodesserts.co.id/

- Accomplishes business development activities by researching and developing marketing opportunities and plans; implementing sales plans; managing staff.
- Accomplishes marketing and sales human resource objectives by recruiting, selecting, orienting, training, assigning, scheduling, coaching, counseling, and disciplining employees; communicating job expectations; planning, monitoring, appraising, and reviewing job contributions; planning and reviewing compensation actions; enforcing policies and procedures.

establishing pricing strategies; recommending selling prices; monitoring costs, competition, supply, and demand.

Host Battle Of Comedy at Media Televisi Indonesia, PT (METRO TV)

November 2012 - November 2013 (1 year 1 month)

- Speak clearly and communicate in a manner that is easy for most people to understand.
- Comprehend information and ideas presented through spoken and written word.
- Identify and understand the speech of different people.
- Communicate information and ideas in writing effectively.
- Develop creative solutions to problems and come up with clever ideas about a given topic or situation.
- Have near-vision to see details at close range (within a few feet of the observer).
- Prepare the (one-liner) jokes, for opening and bridging from comic to comic.

Digital Consultant at SHOUTCAP Inc.

September 2012 - October 2013 (1 year 2 months)

- Making creative content of all client social media channel
- Giving insight of digital marketing for client company time plan
- Looking for potential partner to become client's Key Opinion Leader
- Running the viral activity in social media that connect the dot with event off-air activity

Announcer at Urban Radio

April 2013 - July 2013 (4 months)

Morning Show "Selamat Pagi Bandung.." every weekday 06 A.M - 10 P.M

- Research topics for comment and discussion during shows
- Read prepared scripts on radio shows
- Comment on important news stories
- Provide commentary for the audience during sporting events, at parades, and on other occasions

- Select program content
- Make promotional appearances at public or private events

Digital Strategic Planner at Panenmaya

May 2011 - July 2013 (2 years 3 months)

- liaising with clients to identify specific business problems and develop ideas;
- communicating with colleagues within the agency, such as creatives and account managers, in the process of developing a campaign;
- gaining a comprehensive context for advertising strategies by analysing a wide range of information in great detail, including demographics, socio-economics and the market for the client's product and market share;
- running research groups;

Ex Client: Adira Finance, Astra Honda Motor, Vespa Indonesia, Toyota ,Amway, BRI, Brand's, Phillips,Lee Cooper, Pocari etc

Marketing Manager at Tri Wahana Event Organizer & Talent Management

March 2009 - February 2010 (1 year)

Key Duties/Responsibilities

- Product Marketing: manage the development and implementation of comprehensive marketing plans for events and conferences including direct mail, email, web site merchandising optimization, search engines and social media marketing.
- Product Management: work closely with product development teams on new product development, rollout strategies and product life cycle analyses; identify unique selling propositions and clear competitive differentiation points;
- Budgeting: ensure that product line is within budget.

Sales Center Officer at ANZ

January 2008 - May 2009 (1 year 5 months)

- Promotes the bank's products and services to existing and prospective clients by utilizing available resources.
- Develops and maintains positive relationships with banking clients through excellent customer service.
- Performs sales activities for platinum products available in diverse product lines and multiple markets.

Skills & Expertise

Marketing

Customer Experience Management

Marketing Communications

Social Media Marketing

Strategic Planning

User Acquisition

O2O Business Development

Digital Media

Public Relations

Community Engagement

Brand Development

Social Media

Digital Strategy

Event Management

Digital Marketing

Product Marketing

New Business Development

Product Development

Online Marketing

Education

University of Illinois at Urbana-Champaign

College of Business, 2015

Grade: Digital Marketing Specialization

Universitas Pasundan Bandung

Criminal Justice/Law Enforcement Administration

Languages

English

(Professional working proficiency)

Indonesian

(Native or bilingual proficiency)

Interests

I am interesting to discuss about social media, entrepreneurs, marketing, sales, networking, running, biking, travel, science, startup, technology. Let's have lunch together to share ideas & business opportunities. Request meeting --> http://doodle.com/tomymalewa

Volunteer Experience

Marshall at IndoRunners

August 2013 - Present

Marshall

Organizations

Indo Runners

Marshall

August 2013 to Present

Volunteer

Stand Up Indo Bandung

Board of Director

October 2012 to August 2013

Projects

Digital Tools for Developing Innovative New Products

Members: Erdian Tomy Malewa

how new digital tools are enabling customers to take a more active role in developing and branding the products they consume.

Digital Tools for Persuading Customers to Buy Your Products

Members: Erdian Tomy Malewa

How are products promoted in our digital world? In this module, you learn how new digital tools are enabling customers to take a more active role in promotional activities.

Digital Tools for Effectively Distributing Your Products

Members: Erdian Tomy Malewa

How are products being placed and distributed in our digital world? In this module, you learn how new digital tools are dramatically altering the distribution of products and revolutionizing the retail landscape.

Digital Tools for Setting the Right Prices for Your Products

Members: Erdian Tomy Malewa

How are products priced in our digital world? In this module, you will learn how new digital tools are enabling customers to take a more active role in both evaluating and setting the prices they pay for the products they buy.

TiketTawa.com Feature

Members: Erdian Tomy Malewa

- Used more than 5,000 users in 5 months.
- Almost provided Stand Up Comedy event in 10 cities indonesia.
- Joined with Local Stand Up Comedy community all arround indonesia.

Stand Up Comedy Metro TV

Members: Erdian Tomy Malewa

Sales Achievement

Members:Erdian Tomy Malewa

- Achieve Sterepoint (Reseller) in 20 Across cities indonesia
- Achieve 4 Official Distributor for indonesia market
- Achieve increase 300% company revenue on 3 month

Marketing Achievement

Members: Erdian Tomy Malewa

- ReBranding Stereo Dessert Brand Image on Social Media
- Co-creation new product variant with loyalty customer program
- Product colaboration with TROPICANA SLIM (Nutrifood)
- Joined with the most all favorite event F&B Bazaar in jakarta & bandung.

Erdian Tomy Malewa

Digital Business Storyteller

tomymalewa@about.me



5 people have recommended Erdian

— **Shozo Yamakami**, *Internship(Game Programmer)*, *Touchten Games Pte. Ltd.*, managed Erdian indirectly at Touchten Games Pte. Ltd.

"Erdian has a good curiosity and ambition to achieve his target. He has very high achievement in his life. Very nice to have discussion with him."

— **Tyas Suci**, advised Erdian at Touchten Games Pte. Ltd.

"Tomy is very fun and hardworking person. Never failed to make me laugh, yet still professional when it comes to work. Very nice guy who also can cook. Good to know you, Kang Tom."

— **Dwi Puspita Rini**, *Production Assistant*, *Media Televisi Indonesia*, *PT (METRO TV)*, worked directly with Erdian at Media Televisi Indonesia, PT (METRO TV)

"tomi are friends and co-workers were very inspiring in terms of employment. I learned a lot about digital marketing and social media strategy from him, anyone who worked with him will make the spirit and add insight"

- Luthfi Adham, worked indirectly for Erdian at SHOUTCAP Inc.
- "'Ridiculously creative and friendly' is the phrase that comes to my mind when I think about Erdian. He would be an asset to any company;)"
- **Meidi Dewinta Putri**, *Talent Manager*, *Triwahana Management*, worked directly with Erdian at Tri Wahana Event Organizer & Talent Management

Contact Erdian on LinkedIn